AVALINE AI

San Diego, CA 91942

Phone: 858-35-3908 Email: avaline.ai@gmail.com LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/avaline-ai-b94b89178 Github:https://github.com/Avalineai Portfolio: Write out Link

SUMMARY

Front end developer who solves programming challenges in a team environment and delivers streamlined meaningful client-user experiences. Open-minded teachable optimistic collaborator, with years of experience in intercommunication and problem solving through retail and clerical work. Has a passion for learning quickly and working with new technology while simultaneously helping customers and companies alike in fulfilling their goals and needs.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Technical Skills: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, AJAX, Bootstrap, Node.js, Git, MySQL, AWS

PROJECTS

Project 1 - Link to Github https://github.com/thejihongjin/8-Project-1 **Link to Deployed Project** https://thejihongjin.github.io/8-Project-1/

- First team project utilizing multiple APIs focused on bringing fun, humor, and stress relief to the user experience
- Core responsibilities included researching results of API data structure, and CSS styling
- HTML, CSS, jQuery, Javascript, Bootstrap

Word Guess Game - Link to Github https://github.com/Avalineai/WordGuessGame Link to Deployed Project https://avalineai.github.io/WordGuessGame/

- Themed hangman-style game which takes user input to match against array of strings, and outputs scores and results based on user interaction
- Researched and constructed simple game
- HTML, CSS, jQuery, Javascript, Bootstrap

GifTastic - **Link to Github** https://github.com/Avalineai/GifTastic | **Link to Deployed Project** https://avalineai.github.io/GifTastic/

- Using Giphy API, the project generates themed gifs and also accepts user input to generate additional gifs
- Researched and constructed project
- HTML, CSS, jQuery, Bootstrap

EDUCATION

The Coding Bootcamp-Full Stack Flex Program : UCSD Extension, San Diego, CA 02/2019-current

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in: Browser Based Technologies such as HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Responsive Design, Firebase, and React.js; Deployment utilizing Git and Heroku; Databases such as MySQL and MongoDB;

Server Side Development with Node.js including Express.js, Security and Session Storage, and User Authentication.

B.S Business Administration (online): SNHU, Manchester, NH 2014-2016

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Member Services Representative San Diego Association of Realtors

10/18-current San Diego, CA

- Use critical thinking skills to make decisions, and evaluate possible solutions to solve problems such as conducting research using the internet and resources
- Goal oriented and self driven; will prioritize tasks, and manage time to meet deadlines
- Inspect, identify, and troubleshoot problems with hardware, software, and other equipment
- Perform outreach, negotiate, persuade and counsel people to handle complaints and resolve conflicts; demonstrate comfort when communicating with clients
- Use listening skills to understand oral instructions, and orally convey information and to motivate others
- Learn new procedures, understand and carry out written instructions, communicate in writing
- Build and develop strong client relationships through communication and gain client's confidence
- Identify and present problems to upper management

Key Accomplishments:

- Promoted to manage stand-alone Service Center Office Location in less than 6 months as a new employee
- Learned and used industry specific proprietary software and job-related equipment in less than one week

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

Proposals Department Manager Consumer's Alliance Processing Corporation	2016-2018 Carlsbad, CA
Student Loan Advisor	2016-2016
Student Loans of America	San Diego, CA
Crew Member	2015-2015
Trader Joe's	San Diego, CA
District Trainer Albertson's	2014-2015 Ramona, CA